With all that talk of let it go, I now
have that Frozen song playing in my
head. Yeah, I hope I hope I haven't done
that to you too now. Anyways, so
building on that, I I want to show you
what what I would describe as the
evolution of workflows. Workflow is a
very common word in this field. The
workflow is about how do you go about uh
organizing your activities around this
mysterious magical thing that is a
coding agent. workflow is is really what
Andre Karpathy was getting at with that
tweet. And the way the the the the
optimal workflow with working with with
coding agents has changed uh
consistently with with with what I just
described of the different school of
thought between the two years. So, so
let me take you through uh what I think
of as the six different workflows uh
which which is some somewhat analogous
to to to the eight stages that we
covered yesterday. So in the 2025
mindset there were perhaps three
different levels of of trusting an LLM
at the lowest level of trust where we
began is micromanagement and this is
where you would use an an agent but but
but you and when I say you I mean me
this is definitely was was my mode for
most of last year. I would would very
much like write very specific
instructions in agents.mmd, approve all
of the changes frequently, stop it
running, go back, rewrite agents.mmd,
and then run it again and then check
what it's doing with these frequent
resets. And that was where where I began
and where many people began using some
of these agent coders. And then the next
step was taking a bit of a step back, a
bit more trust. Now, a lot of these
programs, a lot of these coding agents
have a planning mode. You can put them
on plan mode. And when they're on plan
mode, they produce documentation like
sort of to-do lists of what's going to
happen and and you're working together
on figuring out the the plan for what's
to be done. And then when plan mode is
done, you say, "Okay, let's do this."
And you put it onto execution mode. And
so that idea of planning first and then
executing. And typically you execute in
phases. And for each phase, I would have
it go off and build something. Then I
would do a code review and make sure
it's not making a mountain out of a
molehill as they often like to do. And
then after that, I would have it test
and I would come back and review the
test results, do some testing myself,
and then mark it complete and move on to
the next phase. So that is this kind of
plan, execute, review, test, giving it a
little bit more wiggle room, little bit
more more rope, but but generally still
very much on top of things. And then the
next phase is about specd driven
development stdd where you are really
specifying what needs to be done and
then letting it go and do it and it's
been specified. There are there are even
some some sort of spec languages when
you can describe the spec in this very
precise way. And and really the the the
the other term for this is people people
talk about trust but verify. You you you
trust the system, you come back to
verify everything's doing what you
wanted it to do, but you're not doing
the same kind of code review or detailed
testing until till the end. So it's very
much more of a step backwards. uh and
that the trust but verify mindset is
something that that that has become
increasingly common. So these are all
sort of consistent with the 2025
approaches. Okay, now on to the 2026
mindset starting with YOLO. YOLO of
course has been around for for way mo
most of 2025. It's not a new thing, but
I would I would argue that it's only
recently that people are actually using
this beyond just for hobby projects.
People are now using this for real.
That's why I'm putting it in the 2026
mindset category. YOLO, of course, is
when you say, you know what, I don't
need to approve anything. The coding
agent can do whatever it wants. No
permissions needed. So, it's like trust
but verify. Take it to a whole new
level. You could just set this thing
going and go off and have dinner and
come back later and see what it did.
It's never going to stop and ask, "Do
you want to do this or not?" That is the
idea behind YOLO. a whole different
level of trust. And next up are things
called Ralph Loops. Ralph loops were
invented by the Australian developer
luminary Jeffrey Huntley. And it's named
after the Simpsons character Ralph
Wigum. And so the full name is Ralph
Wigumloops. Uh and he's of in Simpsons
is like a sort of naive optimistic
character. And and that is is true to
this design pattern. And here's the
idea. So, so you know that already an
agent is something that calls uh LLM in
a loop to achieve a goal and and it
calls it multiple times until it thinks
it's used its tools enough and it and it
gives some sort of an output. Well, the
idea of Ralph loops is saying, well,
hang on a minute. Can we put this entire
process with this little loop to achieve
an output? Wrap that in another bigger
loop. We will call this agent. We'll
have it do its thing, use its tools,
make some output, and then we'll do a
test to say, has this done enough? Is
this gone has this gone as far as it can
go? Is this as good as it can be? And if
not, make some feedback. Think about
what the gaps are. Add all of that to to
the objectives. And then just call the
whole thing again and have it go off
again and do its loop and come back and
then get some feedback and just simply
call it again and just keep going. Keep
going up to some large number of times
like 10 full times of doing this this
inner loop. 10 big loops of lots of
little loops that is a Ralph Wigum loop
and that idea. here. So, so I said with
YOLO that you could leave something
running over dinner. With Ralph Loops,
you could leave something running
overnight and come back the next day and
it's just done tons. That's the idea of
Ralph Loops. And that is a another whole
new level of trust. And to make this
real for you, this of course is what I
did with this second example yesterday
with with the much more impressive
firstperson shooter game. It was just
the same the same prompt as before, but
I put it in one of these Ralph loops and
I just left it going and I just chugged
away and I came back a lot later and
that's what I had. And it was it was
what we call one shot in that I I didn't
I didn't keep coming back and giving it
more feedback and saying, "I'd like
better graphics. I'd like this. I'd like
this." I just left it doing its own
thing. And it was an LLM that that
decided to come up with the feedback and
to run it again. and it kept going 10
times and that was the output. And so,
you know, that that that's what it does.
And when I say Ralph Loops here, it's a
bit of a point in time. There's a lot of
hype about the these right now. And I
really mean this as an overall category.
It's Ralph Loops and things like that.
Ways to to have a much longer running
task, not something a YOLO is perhaps
something that that runs for an hour.
Ralph loop is is about bigger ways to
run this kind of agentic coding in a way
that's not measured in in in minutes but
it's measured in multiple hours. It's
perhaps something that runs overnight.
It's a longunning process to run
something completely trusted in a way
that you will come back later and see
what it's made with its own internal
feedback mechanism. That's the that's
the bigger concept here. And that leads
to the sixth approach which is then
about multi- aents. This is about it's
it's sort of an extension of Ralph
Loops. In Ralph Loop there there is
another LLM that's doing some of the
feedback potentially. But this is about
where you have many different agents
that are working with different roles.
Perhaps there are testing agents,
feedback agents, there are agents
organized in different categories and
there are manager agents. As we
discussed yesterday, uh it's in some
kind of hierarchy. And these are these
are sometimes called a swarm. If you're
if you're spawning lots and lots of
agents and you talk about orchestration
if you are doing the the kinds of setups
that again that we discussed yesterday
with with the eighth stage. But that
kind of workflow that is really the
ultimate um that is what people at the
forefront of this are doing now in 2026.
So this is how I've seen the workflows
evolve. And of course, this is pretty
similar to Steve Yaggi's different
stages of these coding agents that we
talked about yesterday. And I would say
the the question that I'm sure is on
your mind is is which approach is right?
And you know my the classic answer these
things is that it's not like there's one
approach that's right. It's that
different approaches are right for
different tasks. And I would divide it
into two categories. If you have things
that are that are missionritical where
you're working on enterprise software on
or on like a commercial SAS platform or
you're working with a large code base or
you're working with highly innovative
code like you're trying to generate
something that is going to to maybe use
MCP servers or something like that,
you're at the sort of forefront of what
you're trying to build. Then to me that
lends itself to those those first three
approaches. you're somewhere on that
curve and and so that that would be that
would be one category. But by contrast,
if you are building an MVP like a like a
prototype, a pilot, or you're building
something completely new for the first
time from scratch with an empty
directory, and you have some risk
appetite, you're you're willing to take
some risk and you're trying to generate
a lot of stuff that's fairly boilerplate
like lots of lots of HTML or a React app
or something like that that's going to
involve a lot of fairly cookie cutter
stuff or or or CRUD back end. any of
those kinds of examples, it's going to
lend itself nicely to the the the more
2026 mindset to to these kinds of
approaches. So, so that's that's how I
would uh would would would think about
it. It depends on the kind of project
that you're working on and it depends on
your risk appetite and on whether it's
it's sort of missionritical or not. And
again, you can probably imagine I'm
going to say this, but for me, for most
of what I work on, I am more in that
that top stretch. I work on mission
critical software. Typically, I
sometimes work on on small code bases
and sometimes on large code bases, but
it's often highly innovative stuff. It's
things like connecting with MCP servers,
which typically these current LLMs are
really bad at doing because it's too
it's too new and they don't have enough
training data with those examples in it.
So they they they tend to not use
idiomatic code which which is which is
obviously a big problem. And so I tend
to be in that top category with most of
what I do. But sometimes I am in the
lower category. And so sometimes
particularly if I'm building a pilot or
something, I'm building like a website
to to do something that that could
easily be cranked out then I will use
that second category. And in particular,
when we built our game yesterday, uh, we
used, I guess it was pretty much yolo to
start with and then I did use Ralph
Loops for the second version of it. So,
so I will sometimes be in that second
second strip, but most of my my time is
spent in the top strip. We will of
course cover all of this over the course
of the next few weeks, but yeah, there's
certainly going to be a leaning towards
the more missionritical large codebase
real enterprise development patterns,
how to use this in Angular with a good
nod towards the the more the the the
more 2026 mindset kinds of techniques.
But the one thing I want to stress
beyond all else is and this is this is
particular I know that there are there
are people here from from all of the
spectrum from a senior engineer uh to a
junior engineer or someone just just
starting out and this is particularly
for for people who are more towards the
beginning of their technology career is
that your job in working in this field
is to deliver code that's proven to work
and it's no good to blame the LLM. By
all means, you should use LLM to help
you for sure. It allows us to do a lot
more, but it's still ultimately, of
course, your responsibility to deliver
quality code that works. And saying,
well, the LLM wrote that, that is no
excuse. the LLM wrote it but it's your
job to check its work to validate it and
to pick the right the right stage the
right approach which meets the task at
hand and which is appropriate for what
the what job that you are doing. So
ultimately it is super important that we
all take accountability for the the work
that we deliver uh whether or not we use
LLMs to help us get